<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>austen lamacraft - Blog</title>
		<description>Many body and statistical physics at the University of Cambridge</description>
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.category.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>CUPS Talk</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In the summer I agreed to give a talk to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://camphysoc.co.uk&quot;&gt;Cambridge University Physics Society&lt;/a&gt; a.k.a. CUPS. I took the opportunity to talk about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kardar–Parisi–Zhang_equation&quot;&gt;Kardar–Parisi–Zhang equation&lt;/a&gt; – one of my current obsessions – but also to learn about some new presentation tools. For quite a few years I’ve used &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beamer_(LaTeX)&quot;&gt;Beamer&lt;/a&gt; to create presentations in LaTeX. Presenting mathematics in PowerPoint or Keynote involves too much dragging around of little boxes, which really breaks up the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things move on, however, and in recent years a number of browser-based options for rendering slides in HTML have appeared: things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/Talks/Tools/Slidy&quot;&gt;Slidy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://lab.hakim.se/reveal-js/#/&quot;&gt;reveal.js&lt;/a&gt;, to name just two. I plumped for reveal.js just because it seemed popular and was easy to get going with (and because I was having a crazy term and there was less than a week to go). Also &lt;a href=&quot;http://pandoc.org&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;. You can see the result &lt;a href=&quot;https://austenlamacraft.github.io/Talks/CUPS_KPZ/CUPS_KPZ.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I was pleased with how it turned out, and see myself making the transition to one of these tools in my conference presentations. I’d like to give the very impressive looking &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/impress/impress.js&quot;&gt;impress.js&lt;/a&gt; a try, but perhaps that’s a bit &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; flash.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/blog/talk/CUPS-talk/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/talk/CUPS-talk/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Site</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My web pages are in serious need of an overhaul. In the past I’ve built my sites using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.realmacsoftware.com/rapidweaver/&quot;&gt;RapidWeaver&lt;/a&gt;, but it was never particularly future proof: something always needed updating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m switching to &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, which I used for the first time over the summer. Relative to a WYSIWYG editor it’s a bit more work, but you feel like you know what’s going on under the bonnet. There’s a large ecosystem, lots of &lt;a href=&quot;http://themes.jekyllrc.org&quot;&gt;themes&lt;/a&gt;, free hosting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. The ease of writing in Markdown and rendering mathematics with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathjax.org&quot;&gt;MathJax&lt;/a&gt; is wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;kdmath&quot;&gt;$$
\int f(x)\,dx
$$&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be great to integrate this with &lt;a href=&quot;https://symplectic.admin.cam.ac.uk&quot;&gt;Symplectic&lt;/a&gt; and / or &lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org&quot;&gt;ORCID&lt;/a&gt; to get an automatically updated publication list. Let’s see.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/new-site/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/new-site/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
